

# Efrumiye Aktaş

Electrical Electronic Engineer

## Contact

05072887327

aktas.efrumiye@gmail.com

🤵 Yenimahalle, Ankara, Türkiye

### **About Me**

As a Technical Sales Manager with an engineering background, I have been actively involved in various business processes over the years, contributing to the growth and development of multiple departments within the company. Specializing in customized interconnect solutions for the defense, aerospace, and industrial sectors, I focus on understanding customer needs and collaborating with R&D teams to deliver optimized solutions. Additionally, procurement, I oversee logistics, and marketing operations, ensuring a seamless integration of technical expertise and commercial strategy.

### Education

**Engineering Management** 

2024 - Curent

Master of Science

Hacettepe University

**Management Information Systems** 

2020 - Curent

Bachelor of Science

Anadolu University

**Electrical Electronics Engineering** 

2013- 2018

Bachelor of Science
Uludağ University

## **Experience**

#### **Technical Sales Manager**

2024 - Current

Nicomatic I Ankara

- Managing technical sales operations and business development in defense, aerospace, and industrial sectors
- Leading a multidisciplinary team and collaborating with R&D for customized interconnect solutions
- Developing international sourcing, logistics and market expansion strategies

#### **Sales Engineer**

2021 - 2024

Nicomatic I Ankara

- Providing technical support and special solutions for customer needs
- Collaborating with R&D to develop and optimize product designs
- Monitoring and reporting of projects, determining sales strategies
- Management of marketing activities including fairs, seminars, digital presence and branding
- Supervision of import, export and logistics operations

#### **Production Engineer**

2018-2021

Nicomatic I Ankara

- Design, prototyping and testing of connector and wiring systems
- Preparation of relevant bill of materials and engineering documentation
- Development and planning of production processes to increase efficiency
- Conducting domestic and international supply activities
- Planning and execution of quality and control processes to ensure operational efficiency

## **Skills**

- SOLIDWORKS
- AUTOCAD
- KICAD
- ALTIUM
- MS OFFICE
- MATLAB
- SALES FORCE
- SILOG

## Language

English

## Additional Information

- Driving Licence: B
- UAV 1 Commercial Drone Pilot

#### Intern Engineer

BUGSAŞ I Ankara

• Gained hands-on experience in metro operations, maintenance, and electrical systems

- Received training on ATC, SCADA, power distribution, and safety protocols
- Assisted in troubleshooting and testing electronic and mechanical components

### **Intern Engineer**

6/2016-8/2016

6/2017-8/2017

Havelsan Teknoloji Radar I Ankara

- Experience was gained in radar and military electronic systems, network-supported security systems and the installation, operation, maintenance and modernization of these systems
- Circuits of ongoing projects were tested using electronic simulation programs and printed circuit boards were designed
- Training was received on IP/analog cameras, fiber optic transmission, uninterruptible power supplies, recording devices and camera systems

## Certification

Leadership and Effective Management istanbul NLP Academy	9/2024
Sales Management Training  Campus Online	5/2022
IPC-A-610 Electronic Card Sets Acceptance Criteria Standard Training Nicomatic	3/2021
IPC / WHMA-A-620 Training Nicomatic	1/2021
Solidworks - Advanced Machine Training Yenasoft	4/2019
Solidworks Yenasoft	11/2018